<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Book on Learning CFEngine 3</title>
    <link>http://cf-learn.info/book/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Book on Learning CFEngine 3</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://cf-learn.info/book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 1: Introduction</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/book/chapter01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 22:47:03 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/book/chapter01/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents How to Achieve Automation Home-Grown Scripts Specialized Tools for Automation   Why CFEngine? A Brief History of CFEngine Versions of CFEngine    Every time someone logs onto a system by hand, they jeopardize everyone’s understanding of the system.
  &amp;#8212; Mark Burgess&amp;#44; author of CFEngine   If you are a computer user of any type, you rely on automation every day. Their ability to automate things is what makes computers useful, after all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 2: Getting Started with CFEngine</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/book/chapter02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 07:30:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/book/chapter02/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents Installing CFEngine Which Version of CFEngine? Installing the Community Edition from Source Installing the Community Edition from Binary Packages Installing the Commercial Edition   Finishing the Installation and Bootstrapping Auxiliary Files Your First CFEngine Policy Integrating Your New Policy Into Periodic CFEngine Execution     The first step toward using CFEngine is getting it installed on at least one machine so that you can start playing with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 3: CFEngine Basics</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/book/chapter03/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 19:41:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/book/chapter03/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents CFEngine Basics Basic Principles CFEngine Components A First Example CFEngine Policy Structure Clients and Servers CFEngine Information Resources     CFEngine Basics In this chapter we will take a more detailed look at the basic concepts behind CFEngine, including its theoretical foundation, the syntax and constructs of its policy language, and some unique aspects of its behavior. I will also point you to some of the many online resources available for learning and improving your CFEngine skills.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 4: Using CFEngine</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/book/chapter04/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 07:17:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/book/chapter04/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents Using CFEngine Initial System Configuration User Management Software Installation Using CFEngine for Security Additional CFEngine Features and Information     Using CFEngine We will now explore how to perform some common configuration tasks using CFEngine. Along the way we will encounter more advanced concepts and structures of the CFEngine language.
 Initial System Configuration After a system is installed, a number of routine tasks needs to be performed before declaring it ready for use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 5: The CFEngine Design Center</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/book/chapter05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 18:56:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/book/chapter05/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents The CFEngine Design Center Getting Started with the Design Center Contributing to the Design Center Learning More About the Design Center     The CFEngine Design Center The CFEngine Design Center is a repository of pre-made, ready-to-use components called sketches that allow entirely data-driven system management. You can install, configure, and deploy sketches across your infrastructure without modifying or even looking at the code used to implement them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 6: CFEngine Tips, Tricks, and Patterns</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/book/chapter06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 18:56:06 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/book/chapter06/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents CFEngine Tips, Tricks, and Patterns Hierarchical Copying Passing Name-Value Pairs to Bundles Setting Default Values for Bundle Parameters Using Classes as Configuration Mechanisms Generic Tasks Using Lists and Array Indices Defining Classes for Groups of Hosts Controlling Promise Execution Order Dynamic Loading and Execution     CFEngine Tips, Tricks, and Patterns In previous chapters we have seen a number of CFEngine policies to achieve different specific tasks, with the intention of introducing you to a number of basic CFEngine concepts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>