<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Learning CFEngine 3</title>
    <link>http://cf-learn.info/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Learning CFEngine 3</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://cf-learn.info/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Author</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/the-author/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/the-author/</guid>
      <description>My name is Diego Zamboni, and I am the author of Learning CFEngine 3. I am a computer scientist, consultant, programmer, sysadmin and overall geek, now turned manager. I am very interested in topics related to computer security, virtualization, configuration management and system automation. Currently I work at Swisscom in the Cloud Development Platform team, where I lead teams working on Health Management, Logging and Monitoring capabilities.
During college I founded the first computer security team at UNAM (Mexico&amp;rsquo;s national university), which would grow to become a much larger organization, before moving to the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Code</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/the-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/the-code/</guid>
      <description>These are all the source files included in the book, organized by chapter. Note that in the text, many examples show only fragments of a larger file (for example, when things are explained step by step). In these cases, only the complete file is linked here, and only once per chapter.
Note that the CFEngine Standard Library is not included here, despite several fragments of it being described in the book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Raves</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/the-raves/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/the-raves/</guid>
      <description>Here are some of the nice things people have said about &amp;ldquo;Learning CFEngine 3&amp;rdquo; (since the O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Product Page for the book has disappeared, some of the links are to its last Wayback Machine archive snapshot). In most cases I have only included select quotes, you should follow the links to see the full review or comment.
 The book is excellent. It explains CFEngine 3 in a manner which is easy to understand.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/contact/</guid>
      <description>All fields are required  Your Name Email Address Message   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Release of &#34;Learning CFEngine 3&#34;</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/post/new-release-of-learning-cfengine-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/post/new-release-of-learning-cfengine-3/</guid>
      <description>It has finally happened: a new release of &amp;ldquo;Learning CFEngine 3&amp;rdquo; is here!
Short version   The book is no longer published by O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Media - the new release is published directly by me, and distributed through Amazon as a Kindle ebook, available now. It is also available at a lower price (US$9.99) than the previous release.
 The book now has an index! This has been a very frequent request since the book was first released.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finally, an update about “Learning CFEngine 3”!</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/post/finally-an-update-about-learning-cfengine-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/post/finally-an-update-about-learning-cfengine-3/</guid>
      <description>I know, I know. It’s been over two years since the last post, and other than my occasional comment on the IRC channel or mailing list, you couldn’t be blamed to think that I had disappeared from the face of the earth.  But I’m back! And I have a few updates for you:   I am finally working again on the new release of the book! It will focus on the upcoming CFEngine 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Book</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/the-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/the-book/</guid>
      <description>CFEngine 3 is a mature and widely used tool for configuration management, and Learning CFEngine 3will help you get up to speed with it.
The main audience for this book is experienced system administrators of none-to-medium expertise with CFEngine, but more advanced CFEngine users will also find useful snippets and techniques. Its goal is to guide you from installation to advanced examples and concepts by using examples and techniques that can be put to work straight away.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>&#34;Learning CFEngine 3&#34; at LISA&#39;12</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/post/learning-cfengine-3-at-lisa12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/post/learning-cfengine-3-at-lisa12/</guid>
      <description>Last week I attended the Usenix LISA&#39;12 conference in San Diego, and the awesome people at O&#39;Reilly organized a book signing while we were there. I&#39;d like to share a couple of photos from the event. I had a great time! 
The second release of the book has been out for a few weeks now. If you purchased the e-book from O&#39;Reilly, make sure to check your &#34;My books&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second release of &#34;Learning CFEngine 3&#34;</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/post/second-release-of-learning-cfengine-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/post/second-release-of-learning-cfengine-3/</guid>
      <description>I am happy to announce that as of today, the second release of &#34;Learning CFEngine 3&#34; is available. If you have purchased the e-book version of the book you can get the new release from the &#34;Your Products&#34; page at oreilly.com (pro tip: set up Dropbox synchronization, and you will always have the latest version with you!). And if you haven&#39;t purchased it, now it&#39;s an excellent time to do it!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CFEngine tip #004: How to bootstrap a CFEngine client</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/post/cfengine-tip-#004-how-to-bootstrap-a-cfengine-client/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/post/cfengine-tip-#004-how-to-bootstrap-a-cfengine-client/</guid>
      <description>My apologies for the long delay since the last tip! Today we come back with a simple tip: how to bootstrap a CFEngine client.
First, some background CFEngine is designed to operate in a fully distributed fashion – each CFEngine client (i.e. a machine running cf-agent) can operate fully autonomously, using only the policy files stored locally. For regular operation, cf-agent does not require any type of network connectivity.
In real deployments, of course, maintaining each machine’s policy independently would be impractical, so CFEngine has the concept of a policy hub.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CFEngine tip #003: The distinction between bodies and bundles</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/post/cfengine-tip-#003-the-distinction-between-bodies-and-bundles/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/post/cfengine-tip-#003-the-distinction-between-bodies-and-bundles/</guid>
      <description>This is an extract from Chapter 3 of &#34;Learning CFEngine 3&#34;, where you can also find a much more comprehensive description of bodies and bundles in the CFEngine 3 policy language.
The distinction between bundles and bodies can be confusing at first. Remembering these points may help:
  Bodies are named groups of attributes, whereas bundles are collections of promises. Promises are the units that actually do something in CFEngine (for example, run a command or add a line to a file), whereas attributes specify characteristics of how things are done (for example, whether to run the command in a shell, or where in the file to add the line).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CFEngine tip #002: How to pass arguments to bundles using arrays</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/post/cfengine-tip-#002-how-to-pass-arguments-to-bundles-using-arrays/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/post/cfengine-tip-#002-how-to-pass-arguments-to-bundles-using-arrays/</guid>
      <description>(This tip is based on a section from Chapter 5 of Learning CFEngine 3.)
Many system configuration tasks require groups of name-value pairs as arguments. For example:
 Editing configuration files in which parameters and their values need to be stored (ssh configuration files, Windows-style INI files, etc.) Setting user parameters. In this case, sets of name-value pairs (home directory, full name, shell, etc.) are associated with a single user, identified by name.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get a free copy of &#34;Learning CFEngine 3&#34; in exchange for a review</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/post/get-a-free-copy-of-learning-cfengine-3-in-exchange-for-a-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/post/get-a-free-copy-of-learning-cfengine-3-in-exchange-for-a-review/</guid>
      <description>Are you a technical blogger? O&#39;Reilly&#39;s &#34;Blogger Review Program&#34; allows bloggers to get free ebooks and videos, in exchange for writing reviews of them. 
I&#39;d love to see more reviews of &#34;Learning CFEngine 3&#34;. If you have a technical blog, and would be interested in reviewing the book, I encourage you to visit the program&#39;s website to find out more. 
Plus, I&#39;m sure you will enjoy the book, and I would love to read your review!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day Against DRM at O&#39;Reilly: 50% discount on &#34;Learning CFEngine 3&#34; and all other ebooks</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/post/day-against-drm-at-oreilly-50-discount-on-learning-cfengine-3-and-all-other-ebooks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/post/day-against-drm-at-oreilly-50-discount-on-learning-cfengine-3-and-all-other-ebooks/</guid>
      <description>Today, May 4th, 2012, O&#39;Reilly Media is participating in support of the FSF&#39;s Day Against DRM. All O&#39;Reilly ebooks and videos are DRM-free, and to celebrate this, you can get 50% off on any purchase by using the code DRMFREE.

I&#39;m proud to participate. Learning CFEngine 3 is also available as a DRM-free ebook, and you can use this code to get it at half price. 
Here&#39;s the message from O&#39;Reilly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CFEngine talks at PICC&#39;12 conference</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/post/cfengine-talks-at-picc12-conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/post/cfengine-talks-at-picc12-conference/</guid>
      <description>There will be several CFEngine-related classes and talks at the PICC&#39;12 conference (Professional IT Community Conference) on May 11-12th, in New Jersey. I will be talking about using CFEngine as part of your security infrastructure. My colleague Joe Netzel will be talking about migration from CFEngine 2 to CFEngine 3, so if you are using CF2 and have been considering (or dreading) the migration, make sure to come by! Aleksey Tsalolikhin will give an introductory class to CFEngine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A full shelf</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/post/a-full-shelf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/post/a-full-shelf/</guid>
      <description>I got this photo of a bookshelf at the CFEngine office in Palo Alto. Looks awesome, doesn&#39;t it? :)
    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CFEngine tip #001: Modularize complex policies using methods: calls</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/post/cfengine-tip-#001-modularize-complex-policies-using-methods-calls/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/post/cfengine-tip-#001-modularize-complex-policies-using-methods-calls/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to the new &#34;CFEngine tip&#34; series. In this series of posts I will explore different tips, tricks and techniques for making better use of CFEngine. For now I will post weekly, but the frequency may change as time goes by. If you have any suggestions for topics that I should cover in this series, please let me know! 
For our first installment, we will talk about methods: promises, and how they can be used to make policies both clearer and more extensible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New &#34;reviews&#34; page</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/post/new-reviews-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/post/new-reviews-page/</guid>
      <description>I have started collecting some of the nice things I have read people say about the book, and put them in the Reviews page. Check it out! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My first batch of print books arrived</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/post/my-first-batch-of-print-books-arrived/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/post/my-first-batch-of-print-books-arrived/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m visiting Purdue University today to give a talk and to visit old friends and colleagues. And the first box of books arrived here! It&#39;s incredible to have the physical book in my hand.
 This is the building where I spent most of my grad school years.

  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The bird on the cover of &#34;Learning CFEngine 3&#34;</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/post/the-bird-on-the-cover-of-learning-cfengine-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/post/the-bird-on-the-cover-of-learning-cfengine-3/</guid>
      <description>A lot of people have asked me about the bird on the cover of the book, and I had to admit I didn&#39;t know. Unfortunately, the book (even in the print version) does not include a description of the cover in the Colophon, like most other O&#39;Reilly books. But today I got the information directly from Karen Montgomery at O&#39;Reilly, who designed the cover:
The bird is a Tui, a kind of bird that leaves in New Zealand, also known as a Parson Bird.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CFEngine-related speaking engagements from March 26th-28th, 2012</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/post/cfengine-related-speaking-engagements-from-march-26th-28th-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/post/cfengine-related-speaking-engagements-from-march-26th-28th-2012/</guid>
      <description>I will be giving three CFEngine related talks this week. I would love to see you at any one of them!

 March 26th - Purdue University, Lawson CS Building 3102, West Lafayette, IN, 1:30PM 
&#34;CFEngine 3: Empowering the Next-Generation SysAdmin&#34; 
 March 27th - Chicago Devops Meetup, Morningstar, Chicaco, IL, 5:30PM  
&#34;CFEngine 3: Empowering the Next-Generation SysAdmin&#34; 
 March 28th - CampIT conference on IT Infrastructure &amp;amp; Operations Management, Chicago, IL, 9:00AM</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book status: released!</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/post/book-status-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/post/book-status-released/</guid>
      <description>I am ecstatic to announce that the book is now officially released! You can get it here: http://shop.oreilly.com/product/0636920022022.do. If you purchased the Early Release version, you should automatically be able to download the final version from your &#34;Your products&#34; page at oreilly.com.
It&#39;s been an incredible ride, and it&#39;s an incredible feeling to see it come to this big milestone (I won&#39;t say &#34;the end&#34;, because I know this book will keep evolving).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book status: print-ready</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/post/book-status-print-ready/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/post/book-status-print-ready/</guid>
      <description>I am very happy! I got the notification today that the final book draft has been produced and sent to the printer. This means that over the next few days the final version will be available for purchase, both as e-book and in print form. I will of course let you know when this happens. 
For now, time to enjoy a relaxing weekend, the first with no book-related work in a long time :) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syntax highlighting in &#34;Learning CFEngine 3&#34;</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/post/syntax-highlighting-in-learning-cfengine-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/post/syntax-highlighting-in-learning-cfengine-3/</guid>
      <description>The electronic versions of the book contain full syntax highlighting and other useful features. I&#39;m biased of course, but I think it is both functional and beautiful. Here&#39;s a sample from Chapter 4:
    
The syntax highlighting in my opinion greatly helps in reading the code. Additionally, each one of those numbered callouts in the code are in-document links that take you to the paragraph where that part of the code is described.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CFEngine community event: March 8th, 2012</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/post/cfengine-community-event-march-8th-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/post/cfengine-community-event-march-8th-2012/</guid>
      <description>I am visiting the Bay Area this week, and we took the opportunity to organize a CFEngine community event on Thursday, March 8th, at 6:30 PM. Come by, meet the CFEngine team, hear about some of the exciting things we are working on, and give us your feedback for the future.
Hope to see you there! If you plan to attend please don&#39;t forget to register. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Book status: production</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/post/book-status-production/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/post/book-status-production/</guid>
      <description>Some people have asked me what the status of the book is, so I thought I would post it here. The book is currently in the &#34;production stage&#34;, which means that the draft has been finalized content-wise, and is now being prepared for publication by O&#39;Reilly. They have a specialized group of people for this, who work on preparing nice final versions of the figures, making sure the layout of the book is correct, and doing a few thorough proofreading and editing passes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Searching CFEngine documentation</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/post/searching-cfengine-documentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/post/searching-cfengine-documentation/</guid>
      <description>The CFEngine Reference Manual is extremely useful, and is the ultimate guide to everything about CFEngine. However, it is not always the easiest to find what you are looking for. 
To help in this respect, I have created a cross-referenced index of all the section headings in the manual. You can search it using the second search box on the right of any page of this site. For example, try searching for &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Content-complete</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/post/content-complete/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/post/content-complete/</guid>
      <description>A couple of days ago I finished writing all the material that was planned for the book, so it is now content-complete! I am now going through all the comments that came back from the tech reviewers, and from many readers that sent me feedback while reading the early release. After that it goes to the production department at O&#39;Reilly for putting it in its final form, and then it will be ready for publication!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code examples for &#34;Learning CFEngine 3&#34; now available</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/post/code-examples-for-learning-cfengine-3-now-available/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/post/code-examples-for-learning-cfengine-3-now-available/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m happy to announce that the code examples from Learning CFEngine 3 are now available for browsing and download at http://cf-learn.info/code.html. You can view or download individual files, and also the whole collection. You can also get them from the GitHub repository. 
These examples are extracted automatically from the source files for the book, and as such reflect exactly the current state of what you will find in it. This also means, of course, that as the book evolves you will see changes in the files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CFEngine 3 training on January 25-27th, 2012</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/post/cfengine-3-training-on-january-25-27th-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/post/cfengine-3-training-on-january-25-27th-2012/</guid>
      <description>Quick plug: if you are in the Bay Area and are interested in getting some hands-on introduction to CFEngine 3, please make sure to check out this training session: 
  Automating System Administration using CFEngine 3 Presented by Mark Burgess &amp;amp; Aleksey Tsalolikhin Date: January 25-27 Location: Palo Alto, CA Price: $1950 per person (group discount negotiable) Registration &amp;amp; Agenda: http://cfengine3.eventbrite.com   Mark is the original author of CFEngine and the ultimate CFEngine authority in the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>cf-cmd: A command-line tool for running CFEngine snippets</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/post/cf-cmd-a-command-line-tool-for-running-cfengine-snippets/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/post/cf-cmd-a-command-line-tool-for-running-cfengine-snippets/</guid>
      <description>While writing this book, I&#39;ve had to run hundreds of little CFEngine snippets to run tests, develop examples, verify functionality, or get a solid idea of what some constructs did. After building the typical &#34;test bundle&#34; scaffolding in an editor for the hundredth time, I decided to do something about it. The result is the cf-cmd command. I will let it speak for itself: 
   $ cf-cmd help cf-cmd v1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating from CFEngine 2 to CFEngine 3</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/post/migrating-from-cfengine-2-to-cfengine-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/post/migrating-from-cfengine-2-to-cfengine-3/</guid>
      <description>When designing the CFEngine 3 language, its author Mark Burgess decided a complete overhaul was needed. This decision freed CFEngine 3 from any backwards-compatibility constraints, resulting in a completely new language that is much more flexible, extensible, powerful and expressive. 
Unfortunately, this means that migrating from CFEngine 2 to CFEngine 3 is not automated, and requires a certain level of hand-tweaking. One of the frequent comments I heard at LISA&#39;11 was from people who are currently using CFEngine 2, and have been hesitant of migrating to CFEngine 3 because they are not sure how to proceed, and are afraid of the amount of work it will involve (and also, &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>http://cf-learn.info/ goes live</title>
      <link>http://cf-learn.info/post/http/cf-learn.info/-goes-live/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://cf-learn.info/post/http/cf-learn.info/-goes-live/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m happy to announce http://cf-learn.info/, the accompanying website for my book Learning CFEngine 3, currently in Early Release from O&#39;Reilly. In this website you will find:   General information about the book. A discussion forum for any type of questions, feedback or suggestions about the book. Downloadable code examples from the book, plus (over time) many other new examples. List of Errata, and access to the Errata system at O&#39;Reilly.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>